picaboo.com 2005-12-15

# Picaboo

PICABOO PRIVACY POLICY

Picaboo Corporation ("Picaboo") knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously.  To learn more how Picaboo uses your personal information, please read the following Privacy Policy. By submitting information to us or using any of our services, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy.

WHAT DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVER?  
This Privacy Policy covers Picaboo?s treatment of personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") that Picaboo gathers when you are accessing Picaboo's web pages and when you use Picaboo software or services (collectively, "Services"). This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Picaboo does not own or control, or to individuals that Picaboo does not employ or manage.

WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DOES COMPANY COLLECT?  
The information we gather from customers enables us to personalize our service, fulfill your request for services, limit the use of services, customize content you see, conduct research, provide anonymous reporting for internal and external partners and improve our services.  We collect the following types of information from our customers.  
Personal Information You Provide to Us:

We may receive and store any information you enter through the use of the Services, in connection with your registration to use our software or provide to us in any other way.  When you register as a Picaboo user, we ask for Personal Information, including, but not limited to your email address and name.  Such Personal Information is required for us to perform functions associated with the Services such as sending and receiving albums and comments to and from your Pals (as described below) and notifying users of account status. You may choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of some our features.    
From time to time, Picaboo may also seek Personal Information via voluntary "opt-in" surveys or contests.  Personal Information requested may include contact information (mailing address and phone number) and demographic information (such as zip code or age level).  

The Personal Information you provide may be used for such purposes as informing members of service improvements, scheduled maintenance, feature announcements, newsletters, promotional offers, responding to your requests for certain products and services, measuring the effectiveness of our offerings, customizing content you see and communicating with you about specials and new products.    
When you make a purchase through Picaboo, we do not store your credit card information.  There is more information about your credit card information below.

Picaboo Albums, Recipients, Sharing & Forwarding:

When you use the Picaboo client software, all of your albums and related content are viewable only by you unless you explicitly share them with others.  You, your Recipients and their Recipients can see your albums only when you share them via the Picaboo Network. A Recipient is defined as a Picaboo member with whom you share an album.  When you choose to share your albums with Recipients, those Recipients will be able to view your album online via a link in a browser, or via their Picaboo software if they have installed it. 

Once you share an album, your Recipients can forward that album at will.  Moreover, your Recipients and their recipients will be able to print, create DVDs and order bound versions of the albums you share with them.  

Finally, Recipients may save your albums as their own albums for collaboration of other purposes and may save pictures out of your album on their computers for their own use.  You acknowledge that Recipients could share content that you have restricted through Album Rules by capturing screen shots of such content or taking photos of such content on their screens to share with others.  

Picaboo makes no assurances or warranties that your albums and content are fully protected.  

Your albums and related content may be seen by Picaboo employees or law enforcement agencies only to the extent (i) necessary to evaluate, validate, or correct problems with your account, (ii) the law or legal process requires it, or (iii) it is necessary to do so to protect the rights or property of Picaboo or others.

         Picaboo Pal Invitations:

         A Picaboo Pal Invitee, or Recipient, is someone that you invite to view your album(s). To send an invitation you must provide Picaboo with an email address for the Picaboo Pal Invitee.  Picaboo will not add Picaboo Pal Invitees to a mailing list or send further emails (except to deliver invitations from other Picaboo users), unless they become Picaboo users themselves, in which case they will be subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy.   Picaboo will not sell, rent or distribute Picaboo Pal Invitee email addresses to third parties.  Picaboo may use aggregate non-personal information about Invitees for statistical analysis.

Personal Information Collected Automatically: 

  * We may receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with our Services.  Picaboo may choose to automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser or through the use of the Services including your User ID, IP address, cookie information, the webpage you requested, time of Service access, date of access, Service usage patterns, number of albums shared and received, file size of albums and Service features used. Picaboo collects this data to provide users with a more satisfactory experience, to limit the use of Services pursuant to our Terms of Use, and to monitor system status and customer abuse of the Picaboo Service.  Picaboo will not share such information with any other person or entity in a manner that identifies you as an individual, unless we have your permission. Picaboo does not regularly monitor or collect information on individual pictures or other content within albums other than that which has been described in this Policy.  
  * Generally, our service may automatically collect usage information, such as the numbers and frequency of visitors to our site and its components, similar to TV ratings that indicate how many people watched a particular show.  Picaboo only uses this data in aggregate form, that is, as a statistical measure, and not in a manner that would identify you personally.  This type of aggregate data enables us to figure out how often customers use parts of the website or services so that we can make the website and services appealing to as many customers as possible, and improve those services.  As part of this use of information, we may provide aggregate information to our partners about how our customers, collectively, use our site.   We share this type of statistical data so that our partners also understand how often people use their services and our website, so that they, too, may provide you with an optimal online experience. 
  * Our Service automatically gathers certain information related to the usage and effectiveness of our online self-service support and personal support. We only use such data to help us determine how effective support service is, so we can improve our service and support tools and make them as effective as possible. 

E-mail Communications:

We may receive a confirmation when you open an e-mail from Picaboo if your computer supports this type of program. Picaboo may use this confirmation to help us make e-mails more interesting and helpful.  We may also compare our customer list to lists received from other companies, in an effort to avoid sending unnecessary messages to our customers.  If you do not want to receive e-mail or other mail from us, please notify us by e-mail at support@picaboo.com and include sufficient information for us to identify your account.

What About Cookies? 

  * Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we may transfer to your computer?s hard drive through your browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our site are visited and by how many people.  
  * Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways.

WILL COMPANY SHARE ANY OF THE PERSONAL INFORMATION IT RECEIVES?  
The protection of our users? Personal Information is very important to us.  We neither rent nor sell your Personal Information to anyone.  We share your Personal Information only with your consent or to business partners and affiliates as described below.   
Affiliated Businesses We Do Not Control: We are affiliated with a variety of businesses and work closely with them.  In certain situations, these businesses may operate services at the Picaboo website or sell services or products to you through Picaboo?s website.  In other situations, Picaboo provides services, or sells products jointly with affiliated businesses.  You may generally be able to recognize when an affiliated business is associated with your transaction, and we may share customer information that is related to such transactions with that affiliated business.  For the most part, affiliated businesses are not permitted to market to you directly.  They will do so in conjunction with Picaboo, if at all.

Agents: We may employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you.  Unless we tell you differently, Picaboo?s agents do not have any right to use Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. You hereby consent to our sharing of Personal Information for the above purposes.

Business Transfers: In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets.  In these types of transactions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred.  Moreover, if Picaboo, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, customer information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Picaboo may continue to use your Personal Information as set forth in this policy.

Protection of Picaboo and Others: We may release Personal Information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with any law; enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Picaboo, our employees, our customers, or others.  This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

With Your Consent: Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your Personal Information may be shared with third parties, and will be able to prevent the sharing of this information.

IS PERSONAL INFORMATION ABOUT ME SECURE?  
Your Picaboo account Personal Information is protected by a password-protected database residing within our secure network behind active firewall software for your privacy and security.  Although we will exercise reasonable care in providing secure transmission of information between our servers and your computer, we cannot absolutely ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to us over the Internet.  

You need to ensure against unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account, for example.  

Picaboo uses third party e-commerce providers to manage and fulfill transactions related to the Service such as billing and payment processing.  Any information collected by Picaboo?s third party e-commerce providers is retained on secure pages that are encrypted using the SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) protocol.  These third party providers will collect such information at the time of the transaction.  Picaboo does not store your credit card or other financial information.

WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION CAN I ACCESS?  
Picaboo may allow you to access certain information about yourself for the purpose of viewing, and in certain situations, updating that information.  Such information can be changed and accessed on the Picaboo website under "Customer Support". The types of information that you can access and update will change as our Service changes.

PROTECTION OF CHILDREN.  
The Picaboo Service is not intended for or directed to persons under the age of 13.  Any person who provides his or her information to Picaboo through any part of the Services represents that he or she is 13 years of age or older.

WHAT CHOICES DO I HAVE? 

  * As stated previously, you can always opt not to disclose information to Picaboo, even though it may be needed to receive services or take advantage of certain Picaboo services. 
  * You may be able to add or update certain information on pages, such as those that may be listed in the "What Personal Information Can I Access" section above.  When you update information, however, we may maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. 
  * You may request deletion of your Picaboo account by sending an e-mail to  support@picaboo.com and responding affirmatively to any confirmation e-mails that we may send.  Please note that some information may remain in our records after deletion of your account. 
  * If you do not wish to receive e-mail or other mail from us, please notify us by e-mail at support@picaboo.com, and provide sufficient information for us to identify your account.  Please note that if you do not want to receive legal notices from us, such as this Privacy Policy, those legal notices will still govern your use of the Picaboo website, and you are responsible for reviewing such legal notices for changes. 
  * As explained earlier, the majority of browsers allow you to monitor and restrict our use of cookies. Please note, however, that if your browser does not accept cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of some of our services or website features.

EFFECTIVE DATE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY  
This Privacy Policy is effective as of August 27th, 2004.

CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY  
Picaboo may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time.  Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected.  If we make changes in the way we use Personal Information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on our web site.

QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS  
If you have any questions or concerns regarding privacy at Picaboo site, please send us a detailed message to support@picaboo.com.  We will make every effort to resolve your concerns.

PICABOO CORPORATION  
165 University Ave  
2nd Floor  
Palo Alto, CA 94301
